SHAUN CRAVEN

07972627024

craven6622@googlemail.com

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

My name is Shaun Craven and I am an ambitious and passionate individual. I have excellent leadership, computing, communication and numeral skills and can provide excellent customer service. I am currently studying a level 5 diploma in Full Stack Development and I am looking to pursue a rewarding career with new challenges. I have a very strong managerial background in the retail sector where I have honed my skills over the last 15 years, during which I have been grocery online manager, team manager, assistant store manager and store manager. I have been a store manager for over 5 years and covered multiple shops of various size, and during my time in the role I have implemented a lot of new initiatives and delivered some great results, of which has led me to my latest store of which is the flagship store in the area.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Throughout my career I have always had a keen interest in delivering great customer service and building strong rapport with customers and stakeholders. I have excellent communication and influencing skills and have effectively built relationships with colleagues and customers. I have had the chance to 'WOW' customers in store, at their door and on the phone. I have lead teams of 90+ colleagues, motivating them to achieve daily KPI's.

I currently work for Home Bargains as a store manager. I lead a team of 75 employees and manage average weekly takings of over £250,000. I encourage a greater working environment and take the time necessary to train and develop my team to further drive the store in a more efficient and productive direction. This has resulted in better availability, boosted sales, reduced warehouse holding, less labor use, better staff retention and overall store standards whilst delivering the best customer service in town.

At Farmfoods I was responsible for a team of 16 employees and managed the team, schedules, cash, stock ordering, recruitment and have successfully achieved all KPI's.

Home Bargains – August 2017 to Present Store manager

Farmfoods – September 2016 to August 2017 Branch manager

Sainsbury's – February 2010 to August 2016 Grocery Online driver/ Team Manager

Next – February 2009 to January 2010 Customer Assistant

Boots – September 2008 to January 2009 Customer Assistant/Merchandising Coordinator

INTERESTS

I have a strong interest in music and I play guitar in my spare time. I spend most of my down time building websites and learning advanced coding.

EDUCATION

Code Institute Level 5 Diploma Full Stack Development December 2023 - Present

University of South Wales, Cardiff Grade 2:1 Bsc Hons Popular Music and Technology

September 2011 - June 2014

Young Entrepreneur Award Runner Up - June 2014

SKILLS

Excellent customer service, communication, organisation and time-management skills

Strong knowledge and understanding of retail management and merchandising

Proven leadership skills, able to motivate, develop others, work efficiently to a lean business model.

Strategic planning, problem solving, business planning, marketing and branding

Proficient in HTML, CSS, JAVA, PYTHON and Microsoft Office

Full clean driving license with 18 years driving experience.

REFERENCES

Ian morris - Home Bargains

Area manager

07768625662

Richard Michael – Farmfoods Branch Manager 07951631290

Kim John - Sainsbury's

Store Manager 02920747057